[{"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4bd", "question": "What is the only nation that borders both Nigeria and Gabon?", "answer": "Cameroon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393b1", "question": "Who directed the 1996 movie \"Mars Attacks!\"?", "answer": "Tim Burton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b36e", "question": "What is Ronald Reagan's middle name?", "answer": "Wilson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b6d", "question": "Who won a Best Supporting Actor Oscar for the 2004 movie \"Million Dollar Baby\"?", "answer": "Morgan Freeman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df3", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"trek\"?", "answer": "Afrikaans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca1a", "question": "Toxiphobia is the irrational fear of what?", "answer": "Being poisoned", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2fb", "question": "Who has held the world record in the pole vault, 6.14 m, for more than twenty years?", "answer": "Sergei Bubka", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf04", "question": "What do the letters S and A stand for in SAM missiles?", "answer": "Surface to air", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffe4b7b47818f5674af01b1", "question": "From which novel is this quote \"I\u2019m the most terrific liar you ever saw in your life. It\u2019s awful.\"?", "answer": "\"The Catcher in the Rye\" (The main character, Holden Caulfield, fittingly says this early in the novel while describing himself.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c3e", "question": "What year was Anthony Hopkins knighted by Queen Elizabeth II?", "answer": "1993", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921b", "question": "What instrument did Sting play with the band \"The Police\"?", "answer": "Bass guitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ee", "question": "What two pieces are moved in chess's castling maneuver?", "answer": "The king and rook", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3df7ff048f679a45ab57", "question": "What are beavers called before they are full grown?", "answer": "Kits", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4af249076251badbeabe", "question": "Ruby Bridges became the first Black student to do what?", "answer": "At six-years-old, Ruby Bridges was the first Black child to be integrated into an all-white school in New Orleans in 1960.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ff4", "question": "Arturo Toscanini played what instrument before conducting?", "answer": "The Cello", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59cdb2a265ff7d326b622a76", "question": "What is the fear of mushrooms known as?", "answer": "Mycophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea4072ff048f679a45ab68", "question": "By what name is a quasi-stellar radio source better known?", "answer": "Quasar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee7", "question": "Who was British Prime Minister on V-J day?", "answer": "Clement Attlee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec4", "question": "Who was burnt at the stake by the English at Rouen on May 30th 1431?", "answer": "Joan of Arc", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab1d", "question": "Which continent are the Guiana Highlands located in?", "answer": "South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6559aae7e414034b5aeb5", "question": "Which Norse god\u2019s image is Santa Claus partially based on?", "answer": "Odin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af25653b63e5727cf5a483c", "question": "What century was the model construction system \"Meccano\" created by Frank Hornby?", "answer": "19th century", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a1e1d9cb5a031299b74573c", "question": "What century did the Europeans dicover the Okapi?", "answer": "20th Century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac0b", "question": "What US state is the Catalina Island located in?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d7a", "question": "What Italian phrase for \"from the beginning\" is used in music notation to indicate a repeated passage?", "answer": "Da capo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad46", "question": "What US president was known as \"Father of the Constitution\"?", "answer": "James Madison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59774321284458f1d7854425", "question": "Albert Einstein was offered the position of prime minister of what country?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acce", "question": "Who performed \"The Wall\" by the Berlin Wall?", "answer": "Roger Waters", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5eb73dbc5e259d7869087335", "question": "During the Kentucky Derby races, what fashion event is known as part southern tradition and part spectacle?", "answer": "The Hat Parade", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6a1736c0f9723ab15cb39", "question": "The Ishtar Gate was the main entrance to which ancient city?", "answer": "Babylon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b07c", "question": "What WWII general was known as \"Old Blood and Guts\"?", "answer": "Patton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ef9", "question": "In the Godfather films, what fruit's appearance foreshadows death?", "answer": "Oranges", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b131", "question": "Adlai Stevenson was Senator of which US state?", "answer": "Illinois", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c65e", "question": "When standing in sunlight, what vitamin does your body synthesize?", "answer": "D", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fed261bec223966ae8f8908", "question": "In which city was the very first St. Patrick's Day celebration observed?", "answer": "According to a 2017 research by Dr. Michael Francis, the first recorded celebration of St. Patrick's Day in the world was in the city of St. Augustine in the American State of Florida.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae6a", "question": "What age of exploration began on October 4, 1957?", "answer": "The Space Age", "category": "history"}, {"id": "595642f2803c1f1ebcc4a02e", "question": "Who took home the Academy of Country Music\u2019s Male Vocalist trophy every year between 2006 and 2010?", "answer": "Brad Paisley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b6b", "question": "Which doctor did Hugh Lofting write a series of books about?", "answer": "Dr. Dolittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60121a3a63c99d48cd169b01", "question": "In which state can you be the farthest from a McDonald\u2019s in the contiguous U.S.?", "answer": "Nevada -- A spot in the northwest Nevada is 135 miles from the nearest three McDonald's. They are equidistant from each other.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bccd", "question": "What was the MK2 \"Pineapple\"?", "answer": "A hand grenade", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdfbed0003d27d341092bd1", "question": "What is Antarctica\u2019s tallest volcano?", "answer": "Mount Sidley", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b77", "question": "What patriotic anthem composed by Irving Berlin includes the lyrics \"Stand beside her and guide her\"?", "answer": "God Bless America", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b25401dd7bf43be5e79c", "question": "\"And Bob\u2019s your uncle\" is typically used in which way?", "answer": "Conclude a talking point", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ebc", "question": "In \"Toy Story\", who receives Buzz Lightyear for his seventh birthday and a puppy for his eighth?", "answer": "Andy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c23c", "question": "What does an Apiarist keep?", "answer": "Bees", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a875", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"Haight Street\"?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b176", "question": "In what year did the State of California officially join the United States as its 31st state?", "answer": "1850", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe52fb81bf59ab7d2e38117", "question": "Where is Bank of America headquartered?", "answer": "Charlotte, North Carolina", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392a1", "question": "Mike Judge is best known for creating what two popular characters?", "answer": "Beavis & Butt-head", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015ff52fe83fe1f2a824c4d", "question": "What is the holiday related to the Nativity celebrated by some 12 days after Christmas?", "answer": "Epiphany, which is also known as Three Kings' Day or Little Christmas, is a feast day celebrated by some Christians on January 6th", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abdc", "question": "Where were the 1960 Summer Olympics held?", "answer": "Rome, Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adeb", "question": "Which country was the first to sell its residents' genetic codes to a biotechnology company?", "answer": "Iceland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339097", "question": "In Greek mythology, Hera was the goddess of what?", "answer": "Women and marriage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7bd", "question": "What US territory\u2019s official motto is \"Where America\u2019s Day Begins\"?", "answer": "Guam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc9", "question": "Pretoria is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58dba582874c93a3298b2151", "question": "What name did George Costanza from the TV show \"Seinfeld\" want to name his first child?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e1", "question": "P.J. Clapp is better known by what name?", "answer": "Johnny Knoxville", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedda536ce05a3942286d84", "question": "Brothers Barry, Robin and Maurice Gibb formed which successful pop group in the late 1950's?", "answer": "Bee Gees", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f721aa9e54d890926f6ea", "question": "In which ocean can you find Australia\u2019s Great Barrier Reef?", "answer": "Pacific -- It is comprised of over 3,000 reef systems and contains over 400 different types of coral and is visible from space.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c58e", "question": "Eastern Diamondback, Massasauga and Timber are species of what animal?", "answer": "Rattlesnake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c47", "question": "What popular fashion designer directed the music video for Bjork's \"Alarm Call\"?", "answer": "Alexander McQueen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c8749076251badbead6", "question": "What was the first country to put a woman in space?", "answer": "The Soviet Union -- In 1963, cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova\u00a0orbited the Earth 48 times in a space capsule named Vostok 6.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f3", "question": "What is Tchaikovsky's ballet \"Le Lac des Cygnes\" commonly called?", "answer": "Swan Lake", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a918", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Hood?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e15", "question": "What's the name of the flat, square prison that holds the Kryptonian criminals in the Superman movies?", "answer": "The Phantom Zone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ca", "question": "What is the capital of Arizona?", "answer": "Phoenix", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c824", "question": "What pet bird takes its name from Australian Aborigine words for \"good eating\"?", "answer": "The budgerigar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339515", "question": "Which 1992 western starring Clint Eastwood, Morgan Freeman and Gene Hackman won the Oscar for Best Picture?", "answer": "Unforgiven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a09f", "question": "Who played George Costanza on the TV show \"Seinfeld'?", "answer": "Jason Alexander", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2e0", "question": "The Zimmermann Telegram resulted in US entry into what war?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a90b", "question": "What major river runs through Cleveland?", "answer": "Cuyahoga", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea49b6ff048f679a45abba", "question": "Cephalgia is a medical term for what malady?", "answer": "Headache", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b68b", "question": "\"Lorgnette\" is the proper term for a pair of glasses with what?", "answer": "A handle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb96", "question": "What company has a mascot named Poppin' Fresh?", "answer": "Pillsbury", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ee", "question": "Which river forms part of the border between England & Scotland?", "answer": "River Tweed", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a999", "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano \"Pelee\"?", "answer": "Martinique", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea461dff048f679a45ab9e", "question": "What is the Hawaiian name for yellow fin tuna?", "answer": "Ahi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f77", "question": "What was Gladys Knight's backing band?", "answer": "The Pips", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7ff9d13a3a814d89068c58", "question": "What unit of measurement is approximately 100 fathoms?", "answer": "A Cable", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339053", "question": "Who, in 1874, painted the picture \"La Loge\"?", "answer": "Pierre-Auguste Renoir", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c68e", "question": "What element\u2019s chemical symbol is \"Ni\"?", "answer": "Nickel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42a", "question": "In what country would you see \"whirling dervishes\"?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a027", "question": "Which \"Family Guy\" character is employed as a pilot?", "answer": "Glenn Quagmire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7c2", "question": "NAFTA is a trade agreement between the US and what other two countries?", "answer": "Mexico and Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe769d3eec85e375820b2b2", "question": "Where was \"Cibik Ridge\" in World War II?", "answer": "Bougainville Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338959", "question": "What eye complaint is blamed for the reddish tone of some of Monet's paintings?", "answer": "Cataracts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d119214fea7fe947a2228b", "question": "Which song from The Beatles' the \"White Album\" was originally entitled \"Maharishi\"?", "answer": "Sexy Sadie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0f9", "question": "Which US amendment to the Constitution limits the president to two terms?", "answer": "22nd", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe937656bd93ce3a4e5f66c", "question": "Cyberphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Computers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe902b801dd7bf43be5e86a", "question": "In which city did tennis player Rafael Nadal win his first ever ATP title?", "answer": "Sopot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb20f65ff7d326b622a70", "question": "What is the study of rocks and their formation called?", "answer": "Petrology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff214c731a458464a93c459", "question": "What is the scientific name of the plant used to make liquorice?", "answer": "Glycyrrhiza glabra", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a61d", "question": "Which US state is home to Petroglyph National Monument?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d78", "question": "What movie features three tunnels named Tom, Dick, and Harry?", "answer": "The Great Escape", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b315", "question": "What was created almost 7,000 years ago by the eruption of Mount Mazama?", "answer": "Crater Lake", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd63", "question": "What Indonesian word names the art of successively waxing and dyeing fabric?", "answer": "Batik", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7aa", "question": "What is the atomic number for thallium?", "answer": "81", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59db78b50ab2c8f322317ff6", "question": "What was the name of Nazi Germany's secret police?", "answer": "Gestapo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f16a8af7c52aae91cc07de", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Tempest\", what are the names of the three spirits?", "answer": "Iris, Ceres and Juno", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f07b01dd7bf43be5e7fc", "question": "What is missing in a New England milkshake?", "answer": "Ice cream", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f0cfff048f679a45aaa7", "question": "Tonitrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Thunder", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae3e", "question": "US President Woodrow Wilson was a member of what political party?", "answer": "Democratic Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59cdb45f65ff7d326b622a86", "question": "What is the fear of glass known as?", "answer": "Nelophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a75a", "question": "Cape Cod juts into what body of water?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f32", "question": "Which band member of Mother Love Bone died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Andrew Wood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c890", "question": "What does the Mohs scale measure?", "answer": "Mineral hardness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd69f6f6c0f9723ab15cb2a", "question": "The Parthenon was originally painted in what colors?", "answer": "Red, blue and green", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59008a5dcf842fa4c4ba9690", "question": "What nationality was Johnny Weissmuller?", "answer": "Hungarian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339752", "question": "What was the first silent movie to win the Best Picture Oscar?", "answer": "Wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a860", "question": "Belgium's name is derived from what Roman province?", "answer": "Gallia Belgica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a954", "question": "What Mexican ciudad sits across the Rio Grande from El Paso, Texas?", "answer": "Ciudad Juarez", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a333", "question": "What animal is on the cover of the Beach Boys' album \"Pet Sounds\"?", "answer": "Goat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a40e", "question": "The Thousand Islands are located in what body of water?", "answer": "St. Lawrence River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c45f", "question": "What is the active ingredient in smelling salts?", "answer": "Ammonia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6018bd81d96d05b23b28165b", "question": "The \"girl in the polka dot dress\" was an eye witness in whose assassination?", "answer": "Robert F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60078c700eee65b76b9f2673", "question": "What is the Statue of Liberty holding in her left hand?", "answer": "She holds a tablet inscribed with the date of the U.S. Declaration of Independence \u2014 July 4, 1776. It is nearly 24 ft. long.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe25643658e585fda9cfa36", "question": "What is the name for a smooth transition between yoga positions?", "answer": "Vinyasa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9b83a364247bf200fb87d", "question": "What year was the Steam Workshop opened to allow sharing of user-created content for any game on Steam?", "answer": "2012", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133888f", "question": "Who is Othello's wife?", "answer": "Desdemona", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c894fbde8045e48466dd", "question": "What are the gases that surround the Earth called?", "answer": "Atmosphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015f7a8fe83fe1f2a824c24", "question": "Who was the first woman to contest for the office of the President of the United States of America?", "answer": "In 1872, Victoria Woodhull became the first woman to run for the position of President of the United States.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5a", "question": "What president delivered his \"Fourteen Points\" speech in Congress in 1918?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef660a6ce05a3942286e74", "question": "What Beatles song featured Eric Clapton on lead guitar?", "answer": "\"While My Guitar Gently Weeps\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe2583f658e585fda9cfa3e", "question": "Black Forest cake originates from which country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f1671af7c52aae91cc07b5", "question": "What was the codename of the Allied invasion of French North Africa in 1942?", "answer": "Operation Torch", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be14", "question": "What does a DNR order at a hospital stand for?", "answer": "Do Not Resuscitate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab6d", "question": "What year did Bangladesh declare its independence from Pakistan?", "answer": "1971", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4d964408b8581f80b092a5", "question": "How old did Canada turn on July 1, 2017?", "answer": "150 years old", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c662", "question": "What is the longest and heaviest bone in the human body?", "answer": "Femur", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac5c", "question": "What year did the Chernobyl disaster occur?", "answer": "1986", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59636b6d967692ea851899a5", "question": "Which country, that ceased to be a US territory in 1946, celebrates July 4 as its \"Republic Day\"?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febac287e83c707845b20eb", "question": "What does the X in \"X-ray\" stand for?", "answer": "\"Unknown\" type of radiation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59049c21cf93664eb10486a5", "question": "In which North American city would you find Joe Shuster Way?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4c2749076251badbeace", "question": "How many U.S. Presidents fathered no children?", "answer": "Five -- George Washington, James Polk, Warren Harding, James Buchanan, and Andrew Jackson fathered no children.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c88b", "question": "What does the Bark scale measure?", "answer": "Perceived loudness of sounds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe1f210145fb29466707396", "question": "What is the Christian holy day falling on the Thursday before Easter?", "answer": "Maundy Thursday or Holy Thursday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c68", "question": "What was the name of John Travolta's character in the 1977 movie \"Saturday Night Fever\"?", "answer": "Tony Manero", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339024", "question": "What year did the first \"Where's Waldo?\" illustrated book hit the shelves?", "answer": "1987", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388cf", "question": "How did Alice enter Wonderland?", "answer": "Through a Rabbit Hole", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6008dec2f4f3bc4a292f8629", "question": "On a pirate ship, whose job included maintenance of the ship's hull?", "answer": "Boatswain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b25", "question": "In which museum does the Mona Lisa hang?", "answer": "The Louvre", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5909cfcfbb53d1af658864f6", "question": "What is the curved part of the candy cane known as?", "answer": "The warble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be4e", "question": "Who popularized the \"turducken\" by offering one to the winner of Thanksgiving Day NFL games?", "answer": "John Madden", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339caa", "question": "What hero of 1926 played herself in the 1927 film \"Swim, Girl, Swim\"?", "answer": "Gertrude Ederle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af3", "question": "What was Dr. Seuss' real name?", "answer": "Theodor Seuss Geisel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febd7367e83c707845b2172", "question": "Which NFL team's name was inspired by a famous writer?", "answer": "Baltimore Ravens (The name comes from the poem \"The Raven,\" written by Edgar Allan Poe who called Baltimore home.)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf3", "question": "What year was Frank Sinatra born in?", "answer": "1915", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339929", "question": "What musical, set in New York City, won 10 Academy Awards?", "answer": "West Side Story", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e80433de59ea584496fea3", "question": "Who wrote the 1956 novel \"The Hundred and One Dalmatians\"?", "answer": "Dodie Smith", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec8849ec223966ae8f881e", "question": "Who murders Tommy Williams in the film \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Captain Hadley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133891d", "question": "Who created Iron Man?", "answer": "Stan Lee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c529877e98cb977789ac", "question": "The Griffith Observatory is located where?", "answer": "Los Angeles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a66f", "question": "Washington D.C. is located on the shores of what river?", "answer": "Potomac River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd95", "question": "What was the pseudonym of famous cross-dresser Amandine-Aurore-Lucile Dupin?", "answer": "George Sand", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba4b", "question": "What were the Portsmouth Spartans renamed after the team was moved to Detroit?", "answer": "Detroit Lions", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa3b4dc73aa70ea0b70ae7", "question": "What is the primary mountain range in Iran?", "answer": "Zagros Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7ce23877e98cb97778a3c", "question": "Which country has Damascus as its capital city?", "answer": "Syria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdad", "question": "What food item shares its name with Brad and Janet's hospitable host in \"The Rocky Horror Picture Show\"?", "answer": "A frankfurter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339791", "question": "What KISS star sported the longest tongue in rock?", "answer": "Gene Simmons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a7", "question": "The original TV show \"Star Trek\" aired for how many seasons?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339239", "question": "Who performed \"Bitter Sweet Symphony\" with Coldplay at the Live 8 concert?", "answer": "Richard Ashcroft", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d5", "question": "If it is 1:00 a.m. in Alaska, what would the time be in New York?", "answer": "5:00 a.m.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc2406de0eb824d4052e5", "question": "Norman Rockwell is the official artist of which state?", "answer": "Massachusetts -- He spent 25 years living in the Berkshires of Massachusetts.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b8", "question": "Who played the alien high commander in the TV show \"3rd Rock from the Sun\"?", "answer": "John Lithgow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b3b", "question": "What did Jack Horner pull from his pie?", "answer": "A plum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6017374f44491cbd7c5a1788", "question": "What event led to the first ticker tape parade in New York City?", "answer": "The dedication of the Statue of Liberty on October 28, 1886.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7aa", "question": "Who created the Tabasco sauce?", "answer": "Edmund McIlhenny", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e94cfb75ea27d7a1303aed0", "question": "Which letter represents Potassium on the Periodic Table of Elements?", "answer": "K", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b6991b5e762b54eb9be941c", "question": "Into how many sectors is the standard dartboard divided into?", "answer": "20", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339132", "question": "What year was the second instalment of \"The Faerie Queene\" epic poem published?", "answer": "1596", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe73572eec85e375820b24b", "question": "Who said, \"It\u2019s not enough that we do our best; sometimes we have to do what\u2019s required.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad57", "question": "Queen Mary of England made her reputation by trying to rid her country of what segment of the population?", "answer": "Protestants", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015f84bfe83fe1f2a824c2b", "question": "The first Plague that befell Pharaoh of Egypt was?", "answer": "The first plague that tore through Egypt was the Nile turning into blood", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca6d", "question": "Quercus is the Latin name of what tree?", "answer": "Oak", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339895", "question": "The line \"Greed, for a lack of better word, is good!\" can be heard in what movie?", "answer": "Wall Street", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f9f47abaf848b908361b877", "question": "What was the first feature length animated film ever released?", "answer": "Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a81a", "question": "What Texas city is nicknamed \"The Yellow Rose of Texas\"?", "answer": "Amarillo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a020", "question": "What did Wednesday Addams call her headless doll on \"The Addams Family\"?", "answer": "Marie Antoinette", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b3", "question": "What was Tom Cruise\u2019s character\u2019s name in the \"Mission Impossible\" movie series?", "answer": "Ethan Hunt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7700beec85e375820b2f3", "question": "What is the smallest national park in Canada?", "answer": "Georgian Bay Islands National Park, Ontario", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a02d", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", Stewie took captive the cast of which hit TV show?", "answer": "Star Trek: The Next Generation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015ec8bfe83fe1f2a824c04", "question": "How many Jews did the real-life Oskar Schindler save during the Holocaust?", "answer": "1200", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5d", "question": "Clarence Darrow was coaxed out of retirement to defend what famous duo?", "answer": "Leopold & Loeb", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133992a", "question": "What comedian had a cable special in 1999 titled \"Bigger and Blacker\"?", "answer": "Chris Rock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b063e662d71a53650fc7", "question": "New York\u2019s Guggenheim museum was designed to resemble what?", "answer": "Inverted ziggurat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea379dff048f679a45ab1b", "question": "What element did Joseph Priestley discover in 1774?", "answer": "Oxygen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a44", "question": "What dance craze inspired the 1990 film \"The Forbidden Dance\"?", "answer": "The lambada", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3477ff048f679a45aaf8", "question": "What is the bone diseases that literally translates to \"porous bones\"?", "answer": "Osteoporosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b13", "question": "Whose skull does Hamlet hold and talk to in Shakespeare's play by the same name?", "answer": "Yorick's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e93", "question": "What movie did the villain Verbal Kint appear in?", "answer": "The Usual Suspects", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339635", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named Jasmine?", "answer": "Aladdin's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c193", "question": "Oil wrestling is the national sport of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe768e8eec85e375820b2a9", "question": "What is the record snowfall in Phoenix, Arizona?", "answer": "One inch", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b02a", "question": "What ousted Eastern European leader was executed on Christmas Day in 1989?", "answer": "Nicolae Ceausescu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa3b43c73aa70ea0b70ae6", "question": "What is the oldest city in India?", "answer": "Varanasi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921a", "question": "What female singer is discussed at the start of the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec25e88dc25ca9e12ef643", "question": "Which former member of Genesis had a hit with \"One More Night\"?", "answer": "Phil Collins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c35", "question": "The Grammy Awards are depicted by what gold plated musical object?", "answer": "The gramophone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c0e49076251badbeacc", "question": "Who got married in the very first White House wedding?", "answer": "Dolley Madison\u2019s sister -- Lucy Payne Washington, the sister of First Lady Dolley Madison, married Thomas Todd in 1819.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5989ad41cb8751d53e7d760f", "question": "An 1849 painting by Asher Durand, and a sculpture situated in Bailick Park in Midleton, Ireland,share what name?", "answer": "Kindred Spirits", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396fa", "question": "Who starred as the Six Million Dollar Man?", "answer": "Lee Majors", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeeb", "question": "Which U.S. President ended his country's participation in the Vietnam War?", "answer": "Richard Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff2588c31a458464a93c467", "question": "What does the Slavic word \"vodka\" translate to in English?", "answer": "\"Little water\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aac3", "question": "Which Renaissance City was severely flooded in November 1966?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394cf", "question": "\"Fight the Power\" was a 1990 hit for which group?", "answer": "Public Enemy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c557", "question": "What color does blue litmus paper change to in acid?", "answer": "Red", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7fc", "question": "What is the generation of people born from 1946 to 1964 called?", "answer": "Baby Boomers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ea", "question": "What profession did George Constanza often pretend to be in the sitcom \"Seinfeld\"?", "answer": "Architect", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "595244e2736d4be723796b6a", "question": "How many scents can the human nose detect?", "answer": "More than 1 Trillion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8fefa01dd7bf43be5e85f", "question": "Ablutophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Cleaning, bathing or washing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97f", "question": "What is the official residence of the president of France?", "answer": "Elysee Palace", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394bc", "question": "What is the name of Jack's pet parrot on the TV show \"Will & Grace\"?", "answer": "Guspo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393b7", "question": "Nicole Kidman voiced a character named Norma-Jean in what animated movie?", "answer": "Happy Feet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a33f", "question": "In \"The Walking Dead\" TV show and comics, what was Glenn's occuppation before the outbreak?", "answer": "Pizza delivery boy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4f4", "question": "What is the only bird that can fly backwards?", "answer": "Hummingbird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ad", "question": "In what city would you find Griffith Park?", "answer": "Los Angeles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abfe", "question": "Devils Tower is located in what US state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe737f2eec85e375820b25d", "question": "Which national capital has the coldest average temperature?", "answer": "Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071d593745b36be73039d6", "question": "What operation brought over 1,500 German scientists, engineers and technicians following the end of World War II to the US to aid in military research?", "answer": "Operation Paperclip", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8ab", "question": "Central Europe Time is equal to Greenwich Mean Time plus how many hours?", "answer": "1", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff2100131a458464a93c43b", "question": "Sulaco is a port city in which Joseph Conrad novel?", "answer": "Nostromo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b323204bf195a31e15d738b", "question": "Belmopan is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Belize", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc1676ce05a3942286f11", "question": "Which famous Swedish DJ's name meams the part of hell where the baddest sinners go to?", "answer": "Avicii", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca34", "question": "What geological period followed the Jurassic?", "answer": "Cretaceous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a63", "question": "Who played Rocky's wife, Adrian, in the \"Rocky\" films?", "answer": "Talia Shire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eb021f83302ff91e46499", "question": "Who was the first Beatles bass player?", "answer": "Stu Sutcliffe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd820ecd0de9af39e9d46a0", "question": "What state is home to US' oldest newspaper still being printed?", "answer": "Connecticut", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad9e", "question": "On March 1, 1872, what became the first National Park in the US?", "answer": "Yellowstone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c259", "question": "What is another name for tetanus?", "answer": "Lockjaw", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4de1406d333868d34d70e", "question": "Mustafa Kemal was the first President of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133889c", "question": "Who said: \"I've had such a curious dream\"?", "answer": "Alice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c4c", "question": "Robert Downey Jr. received his first role in which movie?", "answer": "Pound", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac9b", "question": "Who was prime minister of the United Kingdom from 1997 to 2007?", "answer": "Tony Blair", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8cc", "question": "What city is home to the eighty-eight storey Petronas Twin Towers?", "answer": "Kuala Lumpur", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a75", "question": "For what 1997 film did Demi Moore shave her head?", "answer": "G.I. Jane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b220", "question": "What city was Billy Clanton killed in?", "answer": "Tombstone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8acb601dd7bf43be5e770", "question": "Stollen is a traditional fruit-and-nut holiday bread from which country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c5f3fbde8045e48466b3", "question": "A \"bloat\" refers to a group of what animal?", "answer": "Hippopotamus -- A group of hippos consist of 10 to 20 females, their young, and one male hippo.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65833ae7e414034b5aee9", "question": "E. Otis showed what invention at the 1854 World's Fair?", "answer": "Safety elevator", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f51", "question": "What song begins with the words \"Oh, my, God. Becky, look at her butt. It is so big.\"?", "answer": "Baby Got Back", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc5a", "question": "What year was \"Cirque du Soleil\" founded?", "answer": "1984", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc66", "question": "How much did the first Hot Wheels car sell for in 1968?", "answer": "$0.69", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c373", "question": "What disease takes its name from medieval Italian words for \"bad air\"?", "answer": "Malaria", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe905b301dd7bf43be5e87f", "question": "Surprisingly, whose team lost a Christmas-decorating contest when she was an inmate at Alderson, a West Virginia women\u2019s prison?", "answer": "Margaret Stewart", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a899c1660d398dc9cf7a6a3", "question": "Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman god Vesta?", "answer": "Hestia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ae", "question": "What is the name of Johnny Depp's character in \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a012", "question": "What director played a psychiatrist's psychiatrist on \"The Sopranos\"?", "answer": "Peter Bogdanovich", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59bb2a52c9bff04efae6d75f", "question": "What is the birthname of author George Orwell?", "answer": "Eric Arthur Blair", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd1", "question": "What duo's biggest hits are found on 1985's \"Songs from the Big Chair\" album?", "answer": "Tears for Fears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5902a04fcad1ec93f27df769", "question": "What is Cask ale sometimes referred to as in the UK?", "answer": "Real ale", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab75", "question": "What is the capital of Mauritius?", "answer": "Port Louis", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c90d49552800b05cac20f1b", "question": "Tom Hanks won his first Oscar for his role in what film?", "answer": "Philadelphia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b410", "question": "What Shakespearean king was actually king of Scotland for 17 years?", "answer": "Macbeth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1fa", "question": "What was led to Golda Meir's resignation as prime minister of Israel?", "answer": "The Yom Kippur War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b55601dd7bf43be5e7cf", "question": "What is Maxwell House coffee named after?", "answer": "A hotel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd4", "question": "What TV show did \"Family Matters\" spin off from?", "answer": "Perfect Strangers", "category": "entertainment"}]